squaretrade.com 2019-08-26

# Privacy Policy

**1\. Purpose of Privacy Policy**

This privacy policy (" **Privacy Policy** ") describes how SquareTrade, Inc. and its subsidiaries, including, without limitation, CE Care Plan Corp., Complete Product Care Corp, Protection Plan Group, Inc., and ST Product Care Corp (collectively **" **SquareTrade** "**) collect, use, and share personal information of consumer users of on sites where this Privacy Policy is posted (collectively the "Site") as well as our mobile applications that include a link to this Privacy Policy ("Application(s)"). This Privacy Policy explains our online information practices regarding the personal information that we collect about you, how we use that information and the choices that you can make regarding your information on our Site and in our Applications. This Privacy Policy does not apply to websites, applications, or services that do not display or link to this Privacy Policy or that display or link to different privacy statements. SquareTrade is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC). If you have questions or complaints regarding SquareTrade's privacy policy or practices, please contact us at [privacy@squaretrade.com](mailto:privacy@squaretrade.com).

If we change our Privacy Policy, we will notify you here, or by means of a notice on our homepage, prior to those changes taking effect so that you are aware of the information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time, so please review it frequently. ****  

**2\. Types of Information We Collect.**

**We collect two basic types of information – personal information and anonymous information – and we may also combine anonymous information and your personal information with other information in a way that it is not associated with you, to create aggregated information. We collect the following categories of information.**

  * Personal information you provide when you create an account, which may include your first and last name, country of residence, gender, date of birth, email address, photographs, username and password.
  * Personal information you provide when you request information or purchase products or services from us, whether on our Site or through our Applications, including your postal address, telephone number and payment information
  * Personal Information you provide in public forums on our Site and Applications such as quotes, comments, photographs, videos, or other digital media
  * Personal Information sent either one-to-one or within a limited group using our message, chat, post or similar functionality, where we are permitted by law to collect this information
  * Personal Information you provide to us when you use our Site and Applications, our Applications on third-party sites or platforms, such as social networking sites, or link your profile on a third-party site or platform with your registration account
  * Location information when you visit our Site or use our Applications, including location information either provided by a mobile device interacting with one of our Site or Applications, or associated with your IP address, where we are permitted by law to process this information
  * Usage, viewing and technical data, including your device identifier or IP address, when you visit our Site, use our Applications on third-party sites or platforms, or open emails we send

**3\. How We Collect Your Information**

  * We collect personal information you provide to us when you request products, services or information from us, register with us, participate in public forums or other activities on our Site and Applications, respond to consumer surveys, or otherwise interact with us. Please keep in mind that when you provide information to us on a third-party site or platform, the information you provide may be separately collected by the third-party site or platform. The information we collect is covered by this Privacy Policy, and the information that the third-party site or platform collects is subject to that third party's privacy policy. Privacy choices you have made on the third-party site or platform will not apply to our use of the information we have collected directly through our Applications. 
  * We collect information through technology, such as cookies, Flash cookies and Web beacons, including when you visit our Site and Applications or use our Applications on third-party sites or platforms. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can generally change your browser's settings to display a warning before accepting a cookie, or to block all cookies. Visit www.aboutcookies.org to learn about how to delete and control cookies using the main browser types.
  * To make our Site more useful to you, our servers (which may be hosted by a third party service provider) collect information from you, including your browser type, operating system, Internet Protocol ("IP") address (a number that is automatically assigned to your computer when you use the Internet, which may vary from session to session), domain name, and/or a date/time stamp for your visit.
  * As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes IP addresses, browser type, internet service provider ("ISP"), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. We use this information to analyze trends, administer the Site, track users' movements around the Site, gather demographic information about our user base as a whole, and better tailor our services to our users' needs. Except to the extent, if any, noted in this Privacy Policy, we do not link this automatically collected data to your personal information.
  * We may also use third parties to serve ads on the Site and Applications. Certain third parties may automatically collect information about your visits to this and other websites, your IP address, your ISP, the browser you use to visit our Site (but not your name, address, e-mail address or telephone number). They do this by using cookies, web beacons or other technologies. Information collected may be used, among other things, to deliver advertising targeted to your interests and to better understand the usage and visitation of our Site and the other sites tracked by these third parties. This policy does not apply to, and we are not responsible for, cookies or web beacons in third party ads, and we encourage you to check the privacy policies of advertisers and/or ad services to learn about their use of cookies and other technologies. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies click here: <http://www.aboutads.info/choices> or [http://www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/). 
  * We do not currently respond to "do not track" signals or other mechanisms that might enable consumers to opt out of tracking on our Site and Applications.
  * We may also collect non-personal information from your mobile device if you have downloaded our Applications. This information is generally used to help us deliver the most relevant information to you. Examples of information that may be collected and used include your geographic location, how you use the Applications, and information about the type of device you use. In addition, in the event our Applications crash on your mobile device, we may receive information about your mobile device model, software version and device carrier, which allows us to identify and fix bugs and otherwise improve the performance of our Applications. This information is sent to us as aggregated information and is not traceable to any individual and cannot be used to identify an individual.
  * We use third party analytics tools to help us measure traffic and usage trends for the Site and the Applications. These tools collect information sent by your mobile device or our Site, including the web pages you visit, add-ons, and other information that assists us in improving our Site and our Applications. We collect and use this analytics information with analytics information from other users so that it cannot be reasonably used to identify any particular individual user.

**4\. Use of Your Information by SquareTrade.**

In general, personal information that you submit to us is used either to respond to requests that you make, or to aid us in serving you better. We use your personal information in the following ways:

  * To send marketing communications from SquareTrade (including but not limited to newsletters, e-mail, direct mail, phone calls, etc.) 
  * To provide you with the products and services you request
  * To communicate with you about your account or transactions with us, respond to your comments and questions, provide customer service, and send you information about features on our Site and Applications or changes to our policies 
  * With your consent, to post your testimonial along with your name and other information on our Site or in media channels. 
  * When you disclose information about yourself in any SquareTrade online forum, to post that information on our Site, and on third-party sites
  * Consistent with local law and choices and controls that may be available to you
    * To send you offers and promotions for our products and services or third-party products and services
    * To personalize content and experiences on our Site and Applications
    * To provide you with advertising based on your activity on our Site and Applications and on third-party sites and applications. 
  * To optimize or improve our products, services and operations
  * To understand you and your preferences in order to enhance your experience and enjoyment using our Site, Applications, products, and services
  * Consistent with local law, to link or combine your personal information with other personal information we get from trusted third parties to help understand your needs and provide you with better service
  * To detect, investigate and prevent activities that may violate our policies or be illegal
  * In addition, SquareTrade may use and share your personal information with its affiliates, subsidiaries, and partners for purposes of follow-up communications, notices, and/or marketing.
  * _Third Party Advertisements_
    * SquareTrade's websites, online or mobile products or services may employ proprietary or third party ad serving technologies that use cookies, clear GIFs, web beacons, tracking pixels or other technologies to collect information as a result of ad serving through our products or services as well as to help track results. We or third parties operating the ad serving technology may use information such as gender as well as information logged from your hardware or device to ensure that the appropriate advertising is presented to you and to calculate internal ad metrics. We may also use third parties to serve ads on our Sites or to manage our advertising on other sites. Please note that this Privacy Policy does not apply to, and we are not responsible for tracking by third party advertisers. You are encouraged to read the privacy policies of those advertisers, sites, applications or other third parties to learn about their use of cookies and other technology. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, click here: http://www.aboutads.info/choices/.
    * We may use anonymous and aggregated information to analyze request and usage patterns so that we may enhance the content of our services and improve Site navigation. We reserve the right to use anonymous and aggregated information for any purpose and to disclose such information to third parties in our sole discretion.

**5\. Sharing Your Information With Other Companies**

We share personal and other information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this Privacy Policy.

  * When you allow us to share your personal information with another company, such as:
    * If you elect to share your personal information with selected companies so that they can send you offers and promotions about their products and services 
    * If you direct us to share your personal information with third-party sites or platforms, such as social networking sites

**Please note that once we share your personal information with another company, the information they receive is subject to that company's privacy policy and privacy practices.**

  * When companies perform services on our behalf such as our vendors, consultants, and other service providers who work for us and need access to your personal information to provide these services to us. These third parties are prohibited from using your personal information for any other purpose without your specific consent
  * We may share some or all of your personal information with our parent company, subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under a common control ("Related Companies"), in which case we will require our Related Companies to honor this Privacy Policy
  * We may share some or all of your personal information in connection with or during negotiation of any merger, financing, acquisition or dissolution, transaction or proceeding involving the sale, transfer, divestiture, or disclosure of all or a portion of our business or assets to another company (in such case, the company with which we share such information will assume the rights and obligations regarding your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy);
  * In the event of an insolvency, bankruptcy, or receivership, we may transfer your personal information as a business asset (in such case, the company to which we transfer such information will assume the rights and obligations regarding your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy);

Other Disclosures. Regardless of any choices you make regarding your personal information (as described below), we may disclose personal information if we believe in good faith that such disclosure is necessary (a) in connection with any legal investigation; (b) to comply with relevant laws or respond to subpoenas or warrants served on us; (c) to comply with lawful requests by public authorities in accordance with any national security or law enforcement requirements (d) to protect or defend the rights or property of SquareTrade or uses of the Sites or Applications; and/or (e) to investigate or assist in preventing any violation or potential violation of the law, this Privacy Policy, or our Terms of Service.

**6\. Your Controls and Choices**

We provide you with the ability to exercise certain controls and choices regarding our collection, use and sharing of your information. In accordance with local law, your controls and choices include:

  * You may correct, update and delete your registration account.
  * You may change your choices for subscriptions, newsletters, marketing and promotional communications. To unsubscribe from marketing and promotional communications, please click here: https://www.squaretrade.com/mktg-unsubscribe.
  * You may choose whether to receive offers and promotions for our products and services, or third party products and services that we think may be of interest to you.
  * You may choose whether we share your personal information with other companies so they can send you offers and promotions about their products and services.
  * You may request access to the personal information we hold about you and that we amend or delete it. If you completely delete all your personal information, then your user account may become deactivated. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to honor your request. We may retain an archived copy of your records as required by law or for legitimate business purposes.
  * You may stop all collection of information by the Application(s) by uninstalling the Application(s). You may use the standard uninstall processes as may be available as part of your mobile device or via the mobile application marketplace or network.
  * If you decide at any time that you no longer wish to accept cookies from our service for any of the purposes described above, then you can instruct your browser, by changing its settings, to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the websites you visit. Consult your browser’s technical information. If you do not accept cookies, however, you may not be able to use all portions of the service or all functionality of the service. If you have any questions about how to disable or modify cookies, please let us know at the contact information provided below.

Each time you receive newsletters and emails that directly promote the use of our products and services, or third party products and services, you may indicate a preference to stop receiving further communications from us and you will have the opportunity to “opt-out” by following the unsubscribe instructions provided in the email or newsletter or by contacting us directly (please see contact information below). To exercise your controls and choices, or to request access to your personal information, you may (a) change the communication preferences for your account by going to the My Profile page at http://www.squaretrade.com/my-warranties.

Despite your indicated email preferences, we may still send you non-promotional emails, such as emails about your accounts, our ongoing business relations, or to respond to requests and inquiries, or service-related communications, including notices of any updates to our Terms of Service or Privacy Policy.

**7\. Children’s Privacy**

We recognize the need to provide further privacy protections with respect to personal information we may collect from children on our sites and applications. SquareTrade does not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of thirteen for some of the features on our Sites and applications. When we intend to collect personal information from children, we take additional steps to protect children’s privacy, including:

  * Notifying parents about our information practices with regard to children, including the types of personal information we may collect from or about children, the uses to which we may put that information, and whether and with whom we may share that information
  * In accordance with applicable law, obtaining consent from parents for the collection of personal information from or about their children
  * Limiting our collection of personal information from or about children to no more than is reasonably necessary to participate in an online activity
  * Giving parents access or the ability to request access to personal information that we have collected from or about their children, and the ability to request that the personal information be changed or deleted. 

**8\. Data Transfers, Storage and Processing Globally**

We operate globally and may transfer your personal information to our Related Companies or third parties in locations around the world for the purposes described in this privacy policy. Wherever your personal information is transferred, stored or processed by us, we will take reasonable steps to safeguard the privacy of your personal information. SquareTrade complies with the U.S.-EU Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries.  SquareTrade has certified that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement.  To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view SquareTrade’s certification, please visit [http://www.privacyshield.gov](http://www.privacyshield.gov/).

If we transfer personal information received under the Privacy Shield to a third party, the third party’s access, use, and disclosure of the personal data must also be in compliance with our Privacy Shield obligations, and we will remain liable under the Privacy Shield for any failure to do so by the third party unless we prove we are not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.

**A Note to Users Outside of the United States. If you are a non-U.S. user of the Site, by visiting the Site and providing us with data, you acknowledge and agree that your personal information may be processed for the purposes identified in the Privacy Policy. In addition, your personal information may be processed in the country in which it was collected and in other countries, including the United States, where laws regarding processing of personal information may be less stringent than the laws in your country. By providing your information, you consent to such transfer.**

**9\. Notice to California Residents - Your California Privacy Rights (As Provided by California Civil Code Section 1798.83)**

California's "Shine the Light" law, Civil Code section 1798.83, requires certain businesses that share customer personal information with third parties for the third parties' direct marketing purposes to respond to requests from California customers asking about the businesses' practices related to such information-sharing. Alternately, such businesses may have in place a policy not to disclose a customer's personal information to third parties for the third parties' direct marketing purposes if the customer has exercised an option to opt-out of such information-sharing. We have such a policy in place. As described in our Privacy Policy, you can opt-out of our sharing of your personal information with third parties for the third parties' direct marketing purposes by contacting privacy@squaretrade.com. To find out more about your opt-out rights, please review our Privacy Policy or contact us by e-mailing privacy@squaretrade.com or writing to SquareTrade,Inc. Attn: Legal Department, 600 Harrison Street, Suite 400, San Francisco, CA 94107. Please note that under California law businesses are only required to respond to a customer making such a request once during any calendar year.

**10\. Contact Information.**

We welcome your comments or questions about this Privacy Policy or the practices described herein. You may contact us at SquareTrade, Inc. Attn: Legal Department, 600 Harrison Street, Suite 400, San Francisco, CA 94107, or via email at privacy@squaretrade.com.

An individual, under certain conditions, may invoke binding arbitration for complaints regarding Privacy Shield compliance. For additional information, please visit https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=ANNEX-I-introduction.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at [https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request.](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request)

**11\. Modifications to this Policy.**

We may update this Privacy Policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any changes to this Privacy Policy, we will notify you by means of a notice on this Site and within the Application prior to the change becoming effective and we will change the “Last Updated” date above. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

Last updated August 1, 2019.
